MUHAMMAD ADNAN HAQ P.O.BOX 28808 DUBAI, U.A.E.

## **OBJECTIVE**

To achieve a high standard of performance by acquiring the necessary skills and knowledge in my area of work and to work for a reputed organization where I can extend my experience in the Sales and Marketing field and also learn the constantly updated market trends. I have the confidence that I will fulfill the requirement of my Job Profile under all circumstances.

CONTACT # +971 55 355 2820

E-MAIL: xnor84@gmail.com

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Integrated Ideal Solutions LLC (Al Hathboor Group)** since July 2014 till date, as **Sr. Sales and Business Development Manager** 

Job profile:

- Solely in charge for the business development, including the meetings with clients and generating new business alongside maintaining the existing clients
   Reporting directly to the Div Manager, heading the sales dept
- ☐ First point of contact with new and existing clients
- Total business Generated for the previous financial year for 9 Mil AED
- $\hfill \square$
- ☐ Forecasting stock orders to suppliers based on market movement
- ☐ Risk assessment for all clients for approving the credit facility
- ☐ Handling the day to day tasks between coordinators and sub ordinates
- □ Brand Management on behalf of principle companies

Aikah Establishment (MTK and Sons Group) from May 2005 till June 2014, as Senior Sales and Marketing Executive

Job profile:

- Direct sales front for the division. Outdoor and Indoor. Handling walk-in clients as well as Marketing for new clients outdoors
- ☐ Handling the Export clients and the deliveries along with all the necessary documentation required for transport
- ☐ Generated business of Low Voltage switchgear of 6Mil AED for 2013
- Responsible for coordinating the daily sales activities across all the sales outlets of the company; local and overseas
- Approaching new suppliers for potential distributorship and creating a professional relationship with the key account managers from the suppliers
- Attending various sales meetings with the suppliers and negotiating with the terms and conditions
- Solely responsible for the advertising and marketing of the Organization, includes brochure content preparation and co-coordinating with designers for print and online media
- □ Conducting meetings with the suppliers and clients on a regular basis
- Attending meetings with the various suppliers and participating in competitive dialogue
- ☐ Actively participating in competitive marketing discussions with suppliers
- Creating various Weekly, Monthly and Annual reports for the management, reflecting the sales and movement of the stocks and the sales figures and targets completed.
- ☐ Inventory control and maintaining the company stocks at a healthy level

- □ Forecasting and Ordering the Switchgear requirements with the various suppliers of Switchgear, like **Schneider Electric, Himel, Clipsal, Legrand, Lovato**, Oriental Copper and various prestigious European suppliers
- □ Well versed with all the technical aspects involved in the switchgear industry
- ☐ Generating various reports for the Management Meetings
- ☐ Receiving regular Training about the products by the suppliers

#### PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

- Ramp Handling Foundation from Emirates Aviation College, Dubai certified from City & Guilds. U.K.
- > IATA Ticketing Foundation from DCSI, Dubai, Certified by the Ministry of Education, Dubai

# **ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS**

Advanced Higher Diploma in Computer Studies – Certified from Metropolitan University, London (2003-2005)

#### **Modules Covered:**

- ✓ E Commerce (including project) Ways of implementing E commerce in Business
- ✓ Web Development (including project) Developing a Website
- ✓ Programming Techniques (including project) Programming with codes and algorithms
- √ Visual Basic Programming (including project) Software Development
- ✓ System Development
- ✓ Business Communication
- ✓ Business Organization
- ✓ Computer technology
- Various Computer related courses including basics like Ms Office, Web Designing and E-Commerce

#### **EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

Playing cricket for the Company team. Captained the College cricket team (2004). Played college level tennis tournaments. Squash, Tennis, Bowling, Pool and participating in frequent volunteering activities around the city.

## PERSONAL INFORMATION

Birth Date: 12, November 1984

Place of Birth:
Gender:
Male
Marital Status:
Married
Nationality:
Resident of:
Dubai, U.A.E.

#### **VISA STATUS:**

**UAE Residence Visa (Company Sponsorship)** 

### **DRIVING LICENSE:**

Holding valid U.A.E (Dubai) driving license since Feb. 2003

## LANGUAGES:

Fluent in English, Urdu and Hindi and can communicate fairly in Arabic